I couldn't use my locker for weeks because the bolt on the lock reminded me of the one I had put on my lips when the homeless man on the corner looked at me with eyes up merely searching for an affirmation that he was worth seeing. I was more concerned with touching the screen on my Apple than actually feeding him one. When the woman at the fundraising gala said "I'm so proud of you. It must be so hard teaching those poor, unintelligent kids," I bit my lip, because apparently we needed her money more than my students needed their dignity. We spend so much time listening to the things people are saying that we rarely pay attention to the things they don't. Silence is the residue of fear. It is feeling your flaws gut-wrench guillotine your tongue. It is the air retreating from your chest because it doesn't feel safe in your lungs. Silence is Rwandan genocide. Silence is Katrina. It is what you hear when there aren't enough body bags left. It is the sound after the noose is already tied. It is charring. It is chains. It is privilege. It is pain. There is no time to pick your battles when your battles have already picked you. I will not let silence wrap itself around my indecision. I will tell Christian that he is a lion, a sanctuary of bravery and brilliance. I will ask that homeless man what his name is and how his day was, because sometimes all people want to be is human. I will tell that woman that my students can talk about transcendentalism like their last name was Thoreau, and just because you watched one episode of "The Wire" doesn't mean you know anything about my kids. So this year, instead of giving something up, I will live every day as if there were a microphone tucked under my tongue, a stage on the underside of my inhibition. Because who has to have a soapbox when all you've ever needed is your voice? Thank you. (Applause)
No pude usar mi casillero en semanas porque la cerradura me recordaba a la que había puesto en mi boca cuando el vagabundo en la calle me miraba buscando solo una afirmación de que él era digno de ver. Yo me preocupaba más por mi aparato de la manzana que por darle una a él esa mañana. Cuando una señora en la gala por fondos me dijo: "Estoy orgullosa de ti. Debe ser duro enseñar a esos niños tontos y pobres", la respuesta la guarde en un sobre, porque necesitábamos el dinero más de lo que los chicos necesitaban su honra. Pasamos tanto tiempo escuchando las cosas que las personas están diciendo que rara vez prestamos atención a las cosas que no dicen. El silencio es residuo del miedo. Es sentir tus defectos, es morderte la lengua. Es el aire que se retira de tu pecho porque no se siente seguro en tus pulmones. El silencio es el genocidio de Ruanda. El silencio es Katrina. Es lo que se escucha cuando ya no hay más bolsas para cadáveres. Es el sonido después de que la soga ya está tensa. Es el quemar. Son las cadenas. Es el privilegio. Es el dolor. No hay tiempo para elegir tus batallas cuando tus batallas ya te han elegido. No voy a dejar que el silencio se envuelva en torno a mi indecisión. Le diré a Christian que es un león, un santuario de la valentía y brillantez. Le preguntaré al vagabundo su nombre y cómo le fue en su día, porque a veces lo único que todos queremos es ser humanos. Le diré a esa señora que mis alumnos pueden hablar del trascendentalismo como si fuesen Thoreau, y solo porque has visto un episodio de "The Wire" no significa que sepas algo acerca de mis chicos. Así que este año, en lugar de renunciar a algo, voy a vivir cada día como si hubiera un micrófono escondido debajo de mi lengua, un escenario en la parte inferior de mi inhibición. Porque, ¿quién necesita una palestra cuando lo único que se necesita es la voz nuestra? Gracias. (Aplausos)